[Running footsteps]
[REINER] Conny! Have you
found any survivors?
--No.
--[REINER and BERTHOLDT gasp]
No. It's, it's in ruins.
My hometown has been
completely wiped out!
[GELGAR]
Hey. Something's wrong.
You find any bodies?
No.
No, not yet.
How is that even possible?
Titans ransack this place and
there's not a speck of blood?
They must've fled.
The villagers, I mean,
they all escaped.
Uh, your family, too.
You think so?
You think they're alive?
Um. Yeah, sure!
It's the only
logical explanation
for why there'd be
no trace of well, carnage.
[GELGAR] I don't know
that I agree with that.
Suppose the entire village
was evacuated in time.
How do you explain
the devastation?
Why would Titans
rip apart empty houses?
And that doesn't
bother me half as much
as the stables being full.
Without horses, the
villagers' odds of survival
are slim to none.
Anyone not have a torch?
Okay. Let's move!
Our mission is
to evaluate the breach!
[REINER]
Sir!
[TITAN 28A]
Huh. Welcome home.
[CONNY exhales quaveringly]
[Exhales]
[Heart beating]
Huh? Did I?
[REINER]
Snap out of it!
We're falling behind
Gelgar and the others!
Do you hear that?
You had to!
I swear that Titan--
It was only
your imagination.
I didn't hear a damn thing.
Focus on the mission.
But, I... It sounded...
I don't know how, but...
It sounded, like my mother.
Dammit, Conny!
Do you even know
how serious our
situation is right now?
If we don't see this through,
people will die in
the hundreds of thousands!
Just 'cause
your family escaped
doesn't mean they're
out of the woods yet!
Now, you wanna be
a soldier or don't you?
Yeah. Stay focused.
[HORSE neighs]
I'm a soldier!
♪ Opening Song
The closer we get
to the wall,
the less populated
the area will be.
That's good. It didn't
take us very long.
All right.
Let's head to the south.
What's the point?
Last I heard there aren't any
villages to the south of here.
We've raised the alarm
for everyone in the region.
Now we pinpoint the breach.
The idea is to ride along the
wall from the west 'til we do.
Seriously?
You know Christa and me
don't have our
battle gear, right?
What're we supposed
to do about Titans?
The south will be
crawlin' with 'em.
If we can't defend
ourselves, you ought'a just
serve us up on a platter.
Why not let the two of us
withdraw from the front?
Ymir!
Negative. When we find
where they're coming in,
I'll need someone
to relay it HQ.
I know you're scared,
but like it or not,
that's part of the job.
[YMIR sighs]
[CHRISTA] Ymir. Look, I'm aware
of what I've gotten myself into.
Come on.
Hey, no one made me
join the Scouts,
and you know it!
I... I chose it for myself.
I know it's a different
story in your case--
What? Y'think I signed up
for all this crap
because of you?
What other reason do you
have for being here?
You tried talking me into
joining the Military Police
'til you were
blue in the face.
You bowed out
so I'd be eligible!
Don't try to deny it.
I wasn't good enough to
make the top ten on my own.
Ask anybody.
When it comes to skill,
you're the better
soldier by far.
I have no idea
how you did it, but...
Why? Why do that for me?
My family?
That's it, isn't it?
Sure. Why not?
Relax. Don't worry
about it so much.
Take my word for it, sweetie.
I'm only lookin' out
for number one.
[CHRISTA]
Really?
That's such a relief.
[MALE SOLDIER 28A] Steady!
The target is in range!
[MALE SOLDIER 28B]
All cannons, prepare to fire!
[KITZ]
Ready. Aim.
[MALE SOLDIER 28C hollers]
[KITZ]
Fire!
[RICO grunts]
That do the trick?
[MALE SOLDIER 28D]
Nice one, Captain Rico!
We keep this up they'll
never break our defense!
[RICO]
Not necessarily.
The enemy has
strength in numbers.
If they attack en masse,
the line won't have
a snowball's chance in hell.
And worse, something's
off. Really off.
[HANNES]
I don't like this.
[PHIL] Captain Hannes,
sir. What's wrong?
Anyone else
bothered by the fact
we haven't spotted a Titan yet?
You'd think the hole would've
jumped out at us by now.
If where they're
getting in is nearby,
why's it so quiet?
Not that
I mind on principle.
We find the damn thing and
get back without a scrape,
all the better.
[GELGAR breath deeply]
[GELGAR] Please.
Just get it over with.
I can't take this.
Any second now they'll lunge
at us from the shadows.
Dammit. The closer
we get to the entry point,
the more it feels like
we're marching into
the jaws of death.
Ugh! This is driving
me out of my mind!
[GELGAR gasps]
So, you followed the
wall here too, I take it?
That's right. I assume
you found the breach then?
Huh?
We didn't see
any irregularities
along the western route.
Surely you must've seen
something in the east?
[GELGAR] No. The wall's
perfectly intact.
Well, maybe we just
overlooked it?
Not likely. Hole big
enough for Titans
to get through? No way.
I suggest we have
another pass, then.
[NANABA]
That goes without saying.
Trouble is, the horses
are on the verge of collapse
and so are we.
If only we had more light.
[GELGAR]
Huh?
What's that?
[GELGAR] An old castle?
[GELGAR] Not an ideal
place to sleep,
but I guess we can make do
with it for one night.
[NANABA] Yeah. And the moon's
finally out, at least.
[LEVI]
Hey, Four-Eyes.
Since when
are you a geologist?
Or are rocks
just that fascinating?
Looks like you're
about to drool.
What, this?
It's not a rock.
Not an ordinary one, anyway.
It's a hardened piece of skin
left behind by the Female Titan.
[Gasps]
It didn't vanish?
No. This random
fragment broke off
when Annie reverted
back to her human form.
It didn't evaporate.
Didn't simply go "poof."
So that got me thinking.
And when I compared it
with a sliver of the wall,
its texture
and composition were,
for all intents and purposes,
virtually identical.
In laymen's terms
we're hemmed in
by a barricade
of enormous Titans.
If my hypothesis is correct,
the surface was constructed
using consolidated Titan skin.
You're kidding me.
That's what Armin
was trying to say.
[Gasps]
So, then--!
Easy. It's rude to steal
someone else's thunder.
As it stands, we'd be
hard-pressed to find a rock
big enough to plug Wall Rose.
It'd have to be just
the right shape and size,
and we don't have specifics yet.
[ARMIN and HANGE]
But, on the other hand,
where there's
a will there's a way.
Picture Eren utilizing
his hardening ability
while in Titan form.
I could... patch the hole.
The sealant should be composed
of the same material.
And the hardened bit
won't dissolve
once you've transformed back.
This might be less of
a long shot than it sounds.
Thoughts?
Well, anything worthwhile
incurs a little risk.
If we can manage
to shore up Wall Rose,
Wall Maria starts
to look fairly promising.
Vital as it is,
the outpost infrastructure
slows us down to a crawl.
The time and resources needed to
transport materials are immense.
But, if supply wagons don't
have to be accommodated,
we can make our way to
Shiganshina much faster.
And what if we decided
to carry out our plan
in the dead of night?
--[HANGE] Night?
--Yes.
When the Titans
are effectively motionless.
That's not bad.
In fact it's genius.
Particularly if
the group is small enough
to slip by undetected.
The straits we're in
are as dire as they come.
But there might just be
the teeniest bit of slack.
Yeah. Just bear
in mind, though,
the whole plan hinges
on whether or not
Eren can seal a hole, again.
[EREN gasps]
It's, uh, probably
unfair of me to even ask.
But do you think you can?
[LEVI] What he thinks
really isn't the issue.
You either will, or you won't.
That's the reality.
Our comrades are
breaking their backs,
but without you, it's nothing.
Failure isn't an option.
Sir! I know!
I'm prepared to do
whatever it takes!
That's a promise.
My father's cellar.
That's where the answers are.
If there's a grain of
truth in what he told me,
everything depends on
us making it there.
[HANGE]
Here's Ehrmich.
[Gasps]
No one said stop. A rolling
stone gathers no moss.
This is...
Maybe you expected
to see something quaint?
This is what happens
when the walls give.
[BOY 28A sobs]
Mommy! Daddy!
[Gasps]
[LEVI]
No. Take it in, holy man.
These are the faces
of human beings
who've lost everything
they ever had.
Human beings you and your
kind abandoned, incidentally.
Hard to look at it, I'd imagine.
But if the church had its way,
this'd be all of us.
Titans would pour in and
make a feast of what's left.
Shoveling man, woman, and child
down their putrescent gullets.
All humanity
digested as one.
[HANGE]
Once we leave Ehrmich,
we'll be in
Titan territory proper.
Eren. Well enough
to ride a horse yet?
[EREN] Yeah, should be
able to manage one
without much of a hassle.
Saddle up then, soldier.
There's a mount waiting
for you on the left lift.
[EREN]
Right.
Section Commander,
we're pressed for time.
Oh. Thanks, Moblit.
Give me a sec.
So? Seen the light yet,
by any chance?
Oh, goddamn it!
Make up your mind!
This isn't some spiritual test!
Lives are on the line!
Alas, I have no choice.
Neither myself nor
the others who believe
are at liberty
to divulge the truth.
Fat lot a help you are!
Thanks for keeping us company!
It's been fun!
[NICK] I'd offer
my help if I could,
but a duty as great
as this one is beyond me.
The Order of the Walls
abides by the sacred will
--our faith commands us to obey.
--[GIRL] Sir! Thank you, sir!
Whose "sacred will"?
You mean like God,
or something?
I can't answer that.
But what I can do
is provide you with a name.
An individual the sacred will
in its divine wisdom
instructed us to monitor.
Monitor?
It's a person you know.
Someone who enlisted with the
Scout Regiment as of this year.
[ALL gasp]
A child by the name of...
[SASHA]
Important message!
I'm with the 104th Cadet Corps!
Oh, and my name
is Sasha Braus!
[Gasps]
No way.
Who?
Sorry. This is for you,
Section Commander.
You must find her with
all haste. She is the key.
She may know things
we understand but poorly.
And with that,
we come to the end
of what I'm free to share.
[Inhales]
The rest I leave
in your capable hands.
But if, if she's in
the 104th Cadet Corps,
she's at the front lines by now!
Then let's go! Come on!
There's no time to lose!
[SASHA groans]
Watch where you're going!
Sasha?
Just where did you
come from all of a sudden?
I was sent to give a message
to Commander Erwin.
Who, then, entrusted me
to deliver this
to you,
Section Commander!
Oh, uh. Okay, then.
Excellent work.
[Gasps]
[HANGE] So, who is
Nick talking about?
She was the smallest
one in our class.
Golden hair. Blue eyes.
In fact, she's,
uh, kinda cute.
The girl who's always
hanging around Ymir.
Excuse me?
[REINER]
How can you read this?
Ymir. Do you?
Everyone, wake up!
Get to the tower immediately!
[LYNNE] I couldn't
see them in the dark,
but with the moonlight...
How can they move?
This shouldn't be happening!
The sun went down hours ago!
Wh-What's going on?
Hey, guys.
The hell is that?
It's gotta be a Titan,
but have you ever
seen one that big?
Look at it! It's more like,
some kind of beast.
How do we--?
Wait, is it?
It's headed for the wall!
That's the plan.
Are we clear?
[ALL]
Yes, clear!
Right. We have to go! Now!
[LEVI]
Calm down, Eren.
I need you all to listen.
We're going our separate ways.
That's how it has to be.
Erwin had his reasons
for throwing this
ragtag squad together, but right
now this is all riding on you.
Armin, you and Hange
are the brain trust.
Use your combined knowledge to
cook up some kind of solution.
Right. Yes, sir!
Mikasa. I don't think
I'll ever get why
you're so attached
to the guy, but,
put your skills to good use.
Protect Eren at all costs.
Sir! I intend to!
[LEVI] And you.
Don't screw this up.
Hey, hey! Back off!
Don't be coming up here!
Ain't'cha got
nothin' better to do?
Bother someone else.
I should be drinking
right now, damn it!
You're standing between me
and a tankard of ale!
I've earned the right
to get trashed!
[NANABA] Rookies!
Stay where you are!
We've got this.
Let the ODM gear do
what it was designed for.
Attack!
♪
[LEVI]
Check your emotions, Eren.
Learn the meaning
of the word restraint.
If you let yourself succumb to
blind rage, all hope is lost.
We can't afford another mistake.
Sir!
[HANGE]
There's a tower nearby
that'll give us
access to the wall.
Part of an abandoned
fortification to the southwest.
We ride with all haste
for Utgard Castle!
[Intense music plays]
♪ Closing Song